<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>React on xfsnowind</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/tags/react/</link><description>Recent content in React on xfsnowind</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 22:22:49 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xfsnowind.github.io/tags/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to implement Virtualized Grid/List in React</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/react-virtualized/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 22:22:49 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/react-virtualized/</guid><description>
Around 2018, one of my colleague was working on creating a list component which only renders a limited amount of items in the list instead of the whole one to improve the performance if the list is in large or huge scale. I was always interested at how he did that, but I did not do any investment, just an idea. Then once I was asked how to implement such thing during an interview, it remindered me.</description></item><item><title>How to implement a FolderFlip 2</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/folderflip-version2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 22:55:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/folderflip-version2/</guid><description>
Update 2022-11-15: add the images to explain the steps
As we presented in the previous article, we have showed how to implement the FolderFlip with limited number (like 3) items with the position: sticky and IntersectionObserver.
The Problem But it only allows limited number, if it comes more items or the screen is smaller, the items would not be able to scroll. So how would we display if the items are more and the titles take most of the screen.</description></item><item><title>How to implement a FolderFlip with React</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/folderflip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 11:15:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/folderflip/</guid><description>
Haven't updated the blogs for a long time. Just had been struggling on the house work during the whole summer time, painting external and internal wall, new bathroom and etc. But there is still the good news, implemented an interesting frontend component with React, which would inspired by lifeatspotify - borrow the name FolderFlip.
The original idea was come up with by the UX designer in our team, she would like to develop a fancy component which can be used to present the company culture.</description></item></channel></rss>