<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Typescript on xfsnowind</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/tags/typescript/</link><description>Recent content in Typescript on xfsnowind</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 16:20:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xfsnowind.github.io/tags/typescript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Draw a scalable line with React Konva</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/react-konva-draw-line/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 16:20:25 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/react-konva-draw-line/</guid><description>
These days I need to implement a component to draw a line on the given image and this line should be scalable, draggable and limited within the image. So here are the steps to implement it.
Konva Definitely we need canvas to complete it, but instead of using canvas directly, it's better to use some mature library, like Konva
an HTML5 Canvas JavaScript framework that extends the 2d context by enabling canvas interactivity for desktop and mobile applications.</description></item><item><title>Powerful type-checking of React-hook-form and Learning Notes</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/react-hook-form-notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 16:05:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/react-hook-form-notes/</guid><description>
The first time I touched the React-hook-form was in 2020 and it also was the first time I learned React's new concept Hooks. During that time we compared all the popular form libraries, Formik, react-form, final form and etc, but we finally chose the React-hook-form even though it was still under the development during that time. It is because it uses React latest concept Hooks. And React was our fundamental framework in my previous company, so we didn't need to think about the compatibility.</description></item></channel></rss>