<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning Notes on xfsnowind</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/tags/learning-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Learning Notes on xfsnowind</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 16:06:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xfsnowind.github.io/tags/learning-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning Notes From New React Website</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/learning-notes-from-new-react-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 16:06:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/learning-notes-from-new-react-website/</guid><description>
It has been a while after React published its new webiste, I would write down what I learnt from the new webiste.
Describe the UI List Key I know this is an old issue, but I used to use index as the key of list. To summarize it, I will note the correct way to use the key:
Why do we have to use key for the list item? Because the item in the list could be modified, such as insert, deleted or re-sorted, so the React need to know which item the component is responible to.</description></item><item><title>Learning Notes about Image in Frontend</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/blob-buffer-arraybuffer-image/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 16:27:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/blob-buffer-arraybuffer-image/</guid><description>
These days when I handle the image in the frontend, there are some concepts make me confusing. How can we handle the image when saving, uploading and transfering the files? So I want to write some notes about the learning processing here.
What is Blob, Buffer, ArrayBuffer and Base64 format? How to convert them among one another? How can they be used with Image? Concept ArrayBuffer ArrayBuffer is an build-in object in Javascript that represents a generic, fixed-length binary data buffer.</description></item><item><title>Frontend Video Learning Notes</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/frontend-video-learning-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 14:20:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/frontend-video-learning-notes/</guid><description>
These days I am interested at the Frontend video technologies, so did some investigation and want to write learning notes here.
This article would only focus on the frontend technologies, maybe I will write something about the backend in the future maybe, but let's focus frontend here. So to play a frontend html5 video/audio, we need to get familiar with some concepts first.
OK, let's begin from the start point, video.</description></item><item><title>Learning Notes - Git rebase vs Git merge</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/git-rebase/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 20:47:47 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/git-rebase/</guid><description>
Git merge Normally, to get the latest update from main branch during development the feature or fix branch, I would checkout to the main branch and git pull the latest commits and then checkout back and run the merge command.
1git checkout main 2git pull 3git checkout FEATURE-BUG-BRANCH 4git merge --no-ff development 5 6or 7 8git checkout main 9git pull 10git merge FEATURE-BUG-BRANCH main It works and will create a MERGE commit in the feature branch.</description></item><item><title>Learning Notes - Azure Challenge</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/azure-challenge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:48:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/azure-challenge/</guid><description>
This blog is about the Azure developer challenge from Sparebanken Vest. I would like to write the learning notes here.
Explore Azure App Service Target: Learn about the key components of Azure App Service and how App Service can help you create, maintain, and deploy web apps more efficiently.
Azure App Service So what is Azure App Service? It's a Http-based service, which would server for web application, REST APIs and mobile backends.</description></item><item><title>Learning Notes - React Hooks</title><link>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/geektime/react-hooks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 14:50:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://xfsnowind.github.io/blogs/geektime/react-hooks/</guid><description>
This article is a summary when I learned the React Hooks course in GeekTime. Even though we all use React Hooks in the frontend development, I cannot say I understand the internal core and logic of it. So this is a good time to re-learn it through this course. According to my experience, it's definitely better to write down the idea and thoughts down -- The palest ink is better than the best memory.</description></item></channel></rss>